<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>BLOG_NAME</title>
 <link href="YOUR_URL/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="YOUR_URL"/>
 <updated>2013-02-21T17:14:21-05:00</updated>
 <id>BLOG_URL</id>
 <author>
   <name>BLOG_NAME</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The Complete Guide to Verifying Gems with rubygems-openpgp</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/the-complete-guide-to-verifying-gems-with-rubygems-openpgp.html"/>
   <updated>2013-02-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/the-complete-guide-to-verifying-gems-with-rubygems-openpgp</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;The Complete Guide to Verifying Gems with rubygems-openpgp&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;rubygems-openpgp allows you to verify a gem by checking the digital
signature.  This helps to ensure that the gem you are using is
actually the gem published by the author and that it hasn't been
replaced with malicious code.  Lets go over the basics from a gem
user's point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Install the rubygems plugin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install rubygems-openpgp
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Install gpg&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gpg is blah&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Install and verify the test gem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install openpgp_signed_hola --verify
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will probably fail because you don't have the user's public key
yet.  This is required to verify the signature.  Try again with an
option to retrieve the public key automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install openpgp_signed_hola --verify --get-key
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we will retrieve the key so the signature can be verified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;OUTPUT
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why don't we just retrieve the key by default? The first time you need
a public key you will need to download it and store it on a &lt;em&gt;keyring&lt;/em&gt;
that keeps all the public keys you've downloaded. The next time you
need that key you already have access to it. When the next version of
&lt;code&gt;openpgp_signed_hola&lt;/code&gt; is released you'll already have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now imagine a malicious user has hacked my rubygems.org account.  And
he's signed a malicious replacement gem with his key and uploaded it.
When you go to install and verify the package, you'll get a warning
that you don't have the new key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe there's a legitimate reason that the key has changed and you'll
go ahead and load it with &lt;code&gt;--get-key&lt;/code&gt;. But the manual step gives you a
chance to think about things and examine the new key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing you'll want to notice is that we have verified the
signature, but it's listed as UNVERFIFIED:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;OUTPUT
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because even though you've downloaded the key, you have no
idea if it is authentic.  Anyone can make a key with any email and
upload it.  In fact there are several keys out there now that are
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pool.sks-keyservers.net:11371/pks/lookup?op=vindex&amp;amp;search=president%40whitehouse.gov&amp;amp;fingerprint=on&quot;&gt;attributed to president@whitehouse.gov&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Authenticating the key&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because someone can easily create a forged key, you need to
authenticate the key. For the purposes of this discussion, lets be
hand-wavy about that and assume that you've somehow authenticated the
key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Signing the key&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you've authenticated the key you want to issue a signature
saying that you know this is the correct key.  But before you do that,
you'll need to generate a gpg key if you haven't already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Generating your signing key&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg --gen-key
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part you can follow the defaults.  I'll write in more
detail about generating keys in another post, but for now lets just
keep moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Signing the test key&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;BLAH
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Verifying again&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install openpgp_signed_hola --install --verify
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you'll see that the signature is verified and trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;OUTPUT
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Cleaning up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this was just a test and you didn't really verify, lets clean up
the keyring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;delete command
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Using the certificate authority&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authenticating keys can get to be a bit of a pain.  You need to
verify the key for the developers of every gem you need to use.  In a
complex project that can number in the hundreds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A certificate authority steps in as a trusted third-party, issuing
its own signatures against developer keys that it trusts.  Now you, as
the user, only need to decide to authenticate and trust the
certificate authority instead of 100's of individual developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This obviously isn't as safe as performing the verifications yourself,
but provides a reasonable middle ground that saves you time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to use a certificate authority, you need to tell gpg that
you think the key is authentic, and that you trust the signatures it's
issued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Getting the CA key&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Signing the CA key&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Assigning trust to the CA key&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Verifying the test gem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blah blah blah.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>